>> Jem Young: 让我们来谈谈寻找事情，这很重要。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Let's talk about
finding things, this is important.
你今天怎么在你的电脑上找到东西 ?
How do you find things
today on your computer?
>> Jem Young: 这不是骗局，我向你保证。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: It's not a trick question,
I promise you.
>> 扬声器 2:Cmd+F 。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Cmd+F.
>> Jem Young: 是， Cmd+F， Finder，您可以在 Mac 上执行 Cmd+Space ，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, Cmd+F, Finder,
you can do Cmd+Space on Mac,
我喜欢我希望 Windows 能把它捡起来
which I love,
I wish Windows would pick that up.
但在 Unix 系统上，或者在 Linux 系统上，你不能只使用 Cmd+F 。
But on a Unix system, or on a Linux
system, you can't just Cmd+F, necessarily.
你需要点更坚固的东西
You need something a bit more robust.
所以，我们通常会有两种方法去寻找任何东西。
So there's two ways generally
we're gonna try to find anything.
我们会用这个找到的命令我们会用 grep
We're gonna use the find command,
and we're gonna use grep.
我们经常使用 grep ，因为我们是管道输出，我们正在寻找
And we use grep often because we're
piping output and we're searching for
输出中的特定行。
specific lines in the output.
找到，我还没使用，但我们会举几个例子。
Find, I haven't used yet, but
we'll run through a few examples.
找到找到的语法，你想看的地方，你所选择的选项
So find has the syntax of find, the place
you're trying to look, the options you're
试图寻找类似的名字或目录之类的东西
trying to look for, such as name or
directory, something like that.
然后，您正在查找的特定文件，这就是查找语法。
And then the specific file that you're
looking for, so that's the find syntax.
请参考这个
And reference back to this,
因为找到的就是你会忘记如何快速使用的东西
because find is one of those things that
you'll forget how to use really quickly,
因为它是长的而且不一定是直观的
because it's kind of long and
it's not necessarily intuitive.
我只是想找到我所有的日志文件
You're like,
I just wanna find all my log files, and
你就会想到语法
you'll be thinking of the syntax.
因此，我们可以自由地参考这一点。
So feel free to reference back to this.
我给你讲个秘密，我有时候自己参考幻灯片
I'll tell you a secret,
I reference my own slides sometimes
因为我不记得所有这些东西。
[LAUGH] because I don't
remember all of this stuff.
如果你不每天都用它，那就好了，别难过了。
If you don't use it on the day to day,
that's okay, don't feel bad.
别让任何人让你觉得不赖
And don't let anybody make you
feel bad for not remembering this.
除非你是 DevOps 人，否则这些都是你应该知道的。
[LAUGH] Unless you're a DevOps person,
these are things you should probably know.
一些有用的选择是你要找的东西的类型
Some useful options are the type of
the thing you're looking for, the name,
文件是否为空，是否可写?
is the file empty,
is the file executable, is it writable?
稍后，我们将覆盖可执行文件和可写许可权。
And we'll cover executable and writable
in permissions a little bit later.
但如果你想锁定你的系统
But this is pretty useful if you're
trying to lock down your system and
你在说，嘿，我在这个目录里，我是否正确设置了所有权限 ?
you're saying, hey, I'm in this directory,
did I set all my permissions correctly?
这样你就可以搜索所有可写的或者
So you can just do a search for
everything that is writable or
不可写，类似于目录中的内容。
not writable, things like that,
in a directory.
所以让我们去锻炼吧。
So let's run through an exercise.
有点早， [SOUND] 好锻炼吧，
It's a bit early, [SOUND] so
let's do some exercises,
让那些手指动起来
get those fingers working.
因此，请在 var/log中查找所有日志文件。
So find all the log files in var/log.
>> 扬声器 3: 我必须引用 *.log。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: I had to quote *.log.
>> Jem Young: 要点。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Good point.
>> Jem Young: 谢谢。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Thank you.
>> Jem Young: 再次，我并不完美，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Again, I'm not perfect,
我记得这些事我一直都记得
[LAUGH] I remember these
things as I go along.
这对每个人都有希望，希望是这样。
So did that work for
everybody, hopefully, yes.
如果我们想，我们可以对产出进行 grep 。
And if we wanted to,
we can grep that output.
我们可以通过 grep 来管它我们可以说
We can pipe that output through grep,
and we can say,
我想找到所有错误日志或所有访问日志之类的。
I wanna find all of the error logs, or
all of the access logs, things like that.
>> Jem Young: 好的，现在让我们用名称记录来查找所有目录。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: All right, now let's find
all the directories with the name log.
你是说为什么我一直在找日志
You're saying,
why am I always looking for log?
这是你大部分时间做的事因为那是你想做的一件事
It's something you do most of the time,
because that's one thing you're trying to
搜索，您正在尝试查找其中一个日志文件。
search over, you're trying to
find one of your log files.
找到目录，类型，然后找到名称。
So find the directory,
the type, and then the name.
> > Jem Young: 所以我们要做， >> Jem Young: 找到，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So we're gonna do,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: find,
目录，类型，
the directory, the type,
实际上， d，名称是日志。
actually, d, the name is log.
我们得到了很多的允许，因为没有运行 sudo，
And we're getting a lot of permission
denied, because without running sudo,
你不能沉入这些日志中这些都是私人日志
you can't dive into those logs,
cuz those are private logs.